welcome to another darktable tutorial in
欢迎来到中的另一个暗表教程
this video I'll show you how to make
这个视频我将向你展示如何制作
changes to a single image and then apply
更改为单个图像 然后应用
those changes to multiple images at once
同时对多个图像进行这些更改
so this is like batch image editing and
这就像批处理图像编辑和
it's a really powerful feature of
这是一个非常强大的功能
darktable
暗桌
whether you're working with raw photos
无论您使用的是原始照片
or any type of picture really so in this
或者任何类型的图片 真的是这样
example I have some edits that have
例如 我有一些编辑 它们具有
already been applied to these leaves
已经用在这些叶子上了
here so they look a lot different than
所以它们看起来很不同于
the pictures before it but since all of
它之前的照片 但自从所有
these pictures were taken with the same
这些照片是用同样的
camera with the same lighting at the
照明度相同的摄像机
same time roughly we can just take this
同一时间 大致我们可以拿着这个
now and go to copy over here so we have
现在转到这里复制 所以我们有
this history stack we can expand and
这个历史堆栈我们可以扩展和
click copy while that image is selected
选择该图像时 单击复制
and we can copy all the modules to the
我们可以将所有模块复制到
effects that were being applied to it so
应用到它身上的效果
sharpen exposure there's some tone curve
锐化曝光有一些色调曲线
and color correction that happened to it
以及发生在它身上的色彩校正
it was cropped in to be lit more of like
它被裁剪成更像是被照亮了
a widescreen aspect ratio so we'll hit
宽屏宽高比 所以我们将点击
OK to copy all of those and then we can
可以复制所有这些内容 然后我们就可以
select another image and go to paste and
选择另一个图像并转到粘贴 然后
we can just choose which of those things
我们可以选择这些东西中的哪一个
we want to paste and it will paste it on
我们想要粘贴 它会粘贴到上面
then all of a sudden that image looks
然后突然间这张照片看起来
like it as well and we can select by
我也很喜欢它 我们可以通过
holding the control key multiple images
按住Ctrl键多个图像
here and just go over here to paste and
在这里 只要走到这里粘贴和
very quickly we can apply those changes
我们很快就可以应用这些变化
to multiple images so this is a quick
到多个图像 所以这是一个快速
way to do that let me just zoom out here
这样做的方法就是让我放大这里
let's come down to some other pictures
让我们来看一些其他的照片
like these ones of me here and I'm just
就像我这里的这些人一样 我只是
going to do it quick so I did this one
我要做得快 所以我做了这个
here let's double click let's just do
在这里 让我们双击让我们只做
some quick edits to show you an example
一些快速编辑 向您展示一个示例
of this maybe we want to crop in a
也许我们想要插播一段
little bit so we'll do crop and rotate
所以我们将进行裁剪和轮换
we can do that first so we'll do this
我们可以先做那个 这样我们就做这个
widescreen crop and rotate if we wanted
如果需要 可裁剪和旋转宽屏
to change that we can change the aspect
要改变这一点 我们可以改变方面
ratio here to crop to any different type
此处与任何不同类型的裁剪的比率
of like a standard printed image sizes
的标准打印图像大小
or standard image side image sizes for
或标准图像边框图像大小
screens and monitors but let's just do
屏幕和显示器 但让我们只做
this one this is widescreen right here
这张是宽屏的 就在这里
so I'll double click to set that and
所以我会双击来设置它 然后
then we can see if we're curious what's
然后我们就可以看看我们是不是好奇
happening we can always go back to our
如果发生了 我们总是可以回到我们的
original and see how it looked before
原创 看看它以前是什么样子
and the changes were made let's change
改变已经发生了 让我们改变吧
this a little bit here too we can find
我们在这里也能找到一点
something from these more modules and
从这些更多的模块和
sometimes I just like to play with these
有时候我就是喜欢玩这些
infants
婴儿
we just click on them we can see what
我们只需点击它们 就能看到
some of these ones look like like
其中一些看起来像是
colorize I know is just going to oh
我知道彩色化就是为了哦
that's not gonna be there ok we'll do
那不会在那里的 好吗 我们会做的
color correction instead so color
颜色校正改为这样颜色
correction we just get to click this dot
更正我们只需点击这个点
here and we drag it in a certain
在这里 我们把它拖进一个特定的
direction and whatever cover we drag it
方向和我们拖拽的任何掩体
towards is sort of adjust the pixels to
朝向是一种将像素调整为
be more color colorized in that color
在那个颜色里更有色彩
and it's always referencing to the
它总是指的是
center to everything being neutral but
一切都是中立的 但
we can move that Center reference to if
我们可以将该中心引用移动到IF
we do like a green and the orange type
我们喜欢绿色和橙色的
here it's gonna make it look more like
在这里它会让它看起来更像
an Instagram filter a little bit or we
稍微过滤一下Instagram 否则我们
can have it be more in the blue greens
能有更多蓝绿色的吗？
or some blue purples here but it's good
或者这里有一些蓝色的紫色 但这很好
to have if you keep this black dot in
如果你把这个黑点留在里面
the middle and then you just subtly move
中间 然后你只需微妙地移动
this around you can subtly adjust the
这周围你可以微妙地调整
colors a little bit and we can make that
颜色稍微多一点 我们就能做到
look a little bit I don't know how we
听着 我不知道我们怎么
wanted to look maybe we'll make it look
我想看看 也许我们会让它看起来
like that sure let's go to our color
就像那样 好的 让我们来选我们喜欢的颜色
contrast and see if we can make it a
对比一下 看看我们能不能把它变成
little adjustment there so this way if
稍微调整一下 这样如果
we do the green versus magenta it's
我们做绿色对洋红 这是
definitely going to take some of that
我肯定会拿一些这个
redness out of my face which I like and
我喜欢脸上的红晕
then we can add in more some more yellow
然后我们可以再加一些黄色的
and blue too or take that out so we can
或者把它拿出来 这样我们就可以
add in a little bit there it's always
在那里加一点 它总是
hard
硬的
I always make things more exaggerated
我总是把事情做得更夸张
and extreme but let's try and take the
也很极端 但让我们试着用
redness out so that looks a little bit
变红了 所以看起来有点
better there and that was under that
在那里更好 那是在那下面
color contrast and again a lot of these
颜色对比 还有很多这样的东西
I just grab I'll just grab whatever his
我只是抓住我只是抓住他的
have been yet will do that's an easy one
已经做过了 会去做的 这很容易
so the vignette will apply here and this
所以小插曲将适用于这里和这个
is just going to be kind of bring those
就是把那些
gray that shadow in the background a
灰化背景中的阴影
little bit we can adjust this to kind of
我们可以将其调整到某种程度
fit this picture a little bit more just
把这张照片贴得更合适一点
kind of draws the focus more on me draws
把焦点更多地吸引到我的画上
the focus on your subject a little bit a
对你的主题的关注有点像
little bit more okay so we can do that
再多一点 好的 这样我们就可以做了
we can see from the original it looks
我们可以从原件上看到它看起来
like this you know over here and another
像这样 你知道的 这里和另一个
way that we can show the differences
我们可以展示差异的方式
there too if we just go back here let's
那里也是 如果我们回到这里 让我们
just get off of it and yet a little bit
只是摆脱它 但还是有一点
we can go to a snapshot so we come here
我们可以去拍快照 所以我们来这里
to snapshot and we go to original and we
转到快照 我们转到原始版本 我们
go take snapshot
去拍快照吧
and what that's going to do is give us
而这将会给我们带来
an original here we can click on and now
我们可以点击这里的原件 现在
it's it brings up a line that shows us a
它给我们带来了一条线 向我们展示了
difference between our original and our
我们的原版和我们的不同之处
edits right now we're clicked on
编辑现在我们被点击了
original but if we go back to so show
原创的 但如果我们回到这样的节目
our our edit is we can see the
我们的编辑是我们可以看到
difference we see the crop we see the
不同的是 我们看到了作物 我们看到了
colors we see them in getting we see
我们在获取中看到的颜色我们看到了
everything that's going on there and
那里正在发生的一切和
it's kind of cool and we can also click
这很酷 我们还可以点击
in the center of this to rotate it and
在它的中心旋转它和
we can look at it from top to bottom as
我们可以从上到下看它
well so that's kind of a cool way I like
嗯 这是我喜欢的一种很酷的方式
to keep this up actually so I can see
把这个保持下去 这样我就能看到
what's happened with my original image
我的原始图像发生了什么
and how my edits have been applied
以及我的编辑是如何应用的
because sometimes you'll like more
因为有时候你会更喜欢
what's happening in the original but in
在原著中发生了什么 但在
this case I think it's we've definitely
这个案子我觉得我们绝对是
improved this photo some so let's take
改进了这张照片 所以让我们来照一张
this now and let's apply this to some
现在 让我们将其应用于一些
other images so we go back to our light
其他图像 所以我们回到我们的光中
table and we see this is the one that
表 我们看到这是一张
we've done edits to this one I did
我们已经对我做的这一张做了编辑
earlier but if I want to clear the edits
之前 但如果我想清除编辑
on this one I can do that also in this
在这个问题上我也可以在这个问题上做到这一点
area under history stack I can just
历史堆栈下的区域我可以
click on discard and hit yes and it
点击Disard(放弃)并点击YES(是)
makes it go back to how it was before
让它回到了以前的样子
but now I can click this image I can go
但现在我可以点击这张图片我可以去
to copy it brings up this dialog to
要将其复制 将调出此对话框以
select the parts that we want to copy
选择我们要复制的部件
the different modules I hit OK
我点击的不同模块都是OK
and now I can select the image or images
现在我可以选择一个或多个图像
I want to apply them to maybe I'll do it
我想把它们应用到也许我会这么做
to these five all around and just go to
到这五个人周围 然后去
paste and go ok and now all those five
粘贴并继续 好的 现在所有这五个
have that same sort of look so we've got
有着同样的外表 所以我们有
the same look on here and now it's a
同样的样子在这里和现在它是一个
it's snapshotting relative to the
它的快照相对于
picture before it so I can just turn off
在它之前的画面 这样我就可以关掉
the snapshot it right there and we can
快照就在那里 我们可以
see what this looks like so a really
看看这是什么样子 所以真的
really cool feature being able to make
真的很酷的功能 能够使
edits once and apply them to multiple
编辑一次并将其应用于多个
pictures especially if you're working in
图片 尤其是当您在
like a photo shoot but also you it
像是拍照 但也是你
doesn't have to be just photos you could
不一定只是照片 你可以
use this for like web design if you have
如果你有这样的网页设计 你可以用它
a bunch of logos that are all need to be
一堆标志 它们都需要
rotated at once you can really apply
一次旋转 你真的可以应用
this feature it to lots of different
这一特点使它具有许多不同的特点
things when working with pictures and
处理图片时的事项和
image files
图像文件
thanks for watching leave your questions
感谢收看《留下你的问题》
or comments below if you have any and
或下面的评论(如果您有任何和
I'll catch you in the next video
我会在下一个视频中看到你